

DEEPAKR

Team Leader

Contact

Phone 8807433191

E-mail

Deepraj32@gmail.com

Linkedin

https://linkedin.com/in/deepa-kr-23113562

Skills

Project management
Consumer banking specialist
KPI Dashboards & Scorecards
Compliance, banking laws and
regulations

Data mining & Analytics
User Acceptance Testing(UAT)
Enterprise implementations
Risk management
Require gathering & Analysis

Software

EBBS

E-Branch

E-Opal

A Proficiently skilled distinctly focused Team Leader excelling with 8 years of experience in Banking Operations & Cash Management.

Possessing a profoundly distinctive financial acumen, strategic banking skills, problem solving, analytical & technical skills. A strong facilitator adept at working cross-departmentally with co-management, building positive rapport, inspiring trust and guiding teams towards achievement of organizational goals. Thereby, aiming to strengthen a career in with a motive to utilize all the gained knowledge and skills for the betterment of the organization.

Work History

2019 - Nov 16th 2021

2014 – 2016 Officer

Dubai OTT Call back process

2016-2019 Senior Officer (Checker Role)

Initiated
migration
process of
African
Countries and
selfvolunteered
Zimbabwe
process which
include OTT
Manual and
Work flow.

Team Leader, Cash Management Services

STANDARD CHARTERED GLOBAL BUSINESS SOLUTIONS

- Adept at performing banking operations effectively and efficiently, coordinating with various members in the team and managing the various process in banking operations.
- Identified operational issues and devised goals and plans to address them.
- Spearheaded an initiative to increase TAT to boost customer interest resulting in client satisfaction and stake holders.
- Profound knowledge about international, local payments and settlement arrangements, through understanding of swift.
- Maintained operational efficiency with proactive oversight and corrections.
- Developed efficiency in enhancing workflow/process improvements, resulting in implementing Straight Through processing (STP) project for MT103 and MT202 type payments.
- Managing banking operations inclusive of African payments (ITT/OTT/STS/BT) handling 7 countries with agreed TAT in the SLA.
- Call back process in OTT UAE where direct contact with customers and confirming payment details abiding the structured classification of questions.
- Reconciliation for all products/process completed on same day with no exceptions
- Provide on the job training to all new comers and participation in new migration as salary payments in GIS convertor application.
- Following the process/procedure of the bank and ensuring the compliance to rules and regulations of the bank
- AML procedure to be compiled with and all reporting as per policy within the agreed time frame/Escalate any suspicious activities.
- Monitor operational risks legal and compliance requirements and take suitable measurements to mitigate.
- Responsible for audit and risk control standards

GIS

GPS SAMG

CBDR

Filenet

E-Ops

- associated with all products.
- Ensure adherence of all controls and procedures as mentioned in DOI
- Coordinating and reviews of process related documents such as DOI, SLA.KCSA checks.
- Managing customer centric operations by prompt reply to queries and handle transactions in exception cases and solve the cases with mutual rapport with support team.
- Daily Perform of Cash Management Requests
- Supporting and allocating resources to ensure smooth working on BCP day.
- Completing E-learning assessments before due date.
 Process risk review for the unit must be reviewed within agreed span.
- Proactively participated in migration process and identified deviations which followed from other African countries.

PROJECTS

- Completed in depth analyses for business optimization projects, reporting tools, back office programs and payment processing apps
- provided executives with analytics and decision support tools used as the basis for re organization, consolidation and relocation strategies
- Partnered with support team to automate manual processes, saving time and money while decreasing errors.
- Performed quality assurance, system integration and user acceptance testing facilitating on time, on budget and acclaimed go live of enterprise implementations.

Education

2010 - 2012 **MBA: HR & Finance**

Bhilai Institute of Technology - Chhattisgarh

2007 - 2010 BA Economics: Foreign Trade

VTB College - Kerela

Accomplishments

Honored with "Star of the Month" award for continuous excellence at work.